<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title>Blog - theDavidBarton.github.io</title>
  <link>https://theDavidBarton.github.io/blog</link>
  <description>Blog by David Barton</description>
  <title>Obfuscate e-mail smart</title><link>https://theDavidBarton.github.io/obfuscate-email-smart</link><pubDate>Wed, Jan 20, 2021</pubDate><description>How to prevent e-mails efficiently from crawling.</description>
<title>Puppeteer: Chromium instances remain active in the background after browser.disconnect</title><link>https://theDavidBarton.github.io/chromium-instances-remain-active-in-the-background-after-browser-disconnect</link><pubDate>Tue, Jan 12, 2021</pubDate><description>How to solve the infamous zombie Chromium instance issue on Windows.</description>
<title>How to check SSL cert with puppeteer?</title><link>https://theDavidBarton.github.io/cert-expiry-puppeteer</link><pubDate>Sat, Dec 12, 2020</pubDate><description>Frustrating it is when you miss to renew your SSL cert on any of your domains. And it is hell of a job to check the different expiry dates among sites manually. with the help of puppeteer you can do it automatically.</description>
<title>How to automate date selection with puppeteer?</title><link>https://theDavidBarton.github.io/automate-a-calendar</link><pubDate>Tue, Oct 20, 2020</pubDate><description>When it comes to form e2e automation calendars and date pickers are the trickyest to be implemented. Or at least to make a general solution that can automate any calendar UI-s.</description>
<title>[FREE] Online Conferences for 2020 fall</title><link>https://theDavidBarton.github.io/conferences-online-2020-fall</link><pubDate>Mon, Oct 19, 2020</pubDate><description>📅 For October-December I can recommend these free online events.</description>
<title>Anonymous IIFE-s and semicolons</title><link>https://theDavidBarton.github.io/anonymous-IIFE-fn</link><pubDate>Sun, Oct 11, 2020</pubDate><description>IIFE is an elegant way to execute what should be executed anyway in our JavaScript code. If it is also an anonymous function then it is almost sure that the returned value is not used later on. When it comes to semicolon-less JavaScript styles it gets tricky (and ugly). Let's see how we can handle it if we want to gain from the advantages of both approaches.</description>

<title>Stolen by a robot (Strange days indeed)</title><link>https://theDavidBarton.github.io/stolen-by-a-robot</link><pubDate>Mon, Oct 5, 2020</pubDate><description>Lately I've found a strange phenomenon, that one of my Guitar Pro tabs (tabbed in August 2005) was exported as a standalone song by someone and was published on Spotify. Strange days indeed.</description>
<title>Chrome DevTools: $(selector) shorthand doesn't return the element while $$(selector)[0] does</title><link>https://theDavidBarton.github.io/devtools-dollar-shorthand-jquery</link><pubDate>Tue, Sep 29, 2020</pubDate><description>Time to time I face a weird phenomenon with the $ chrome api shorthand for document.querySelector that it doesn't return the element with the correct selector, while it works correctly with $$. As puppeteer heavily depends on these shorthands (page.$, page.$$, page.$eval, page.$$eval) it can cause unexpected issues.</description>
<title>Iterating puppeteer async methods in for loop vs. Array.map()/Array.forEach()</title><link>https://theDavidBarton.github.io/iterating-puppeteer-async-methods</link><pubDate>Sat, Jun 27, 2020</pubDate><description>As all puppeteer methods are asynchronous it doesn't matter how we iterate over them. I've made a comparison and a rating of the most commonly recommended and used options.</description>
<title>Simple preloader CSS animation</title><link>https://theDavidBarton.github.io/simple-preloader</link><pubDate>Wed, Feb 5, 2020</pubDate><description>Previously I was working on a redirect page to act as a bridge between my page and my idling Heroku apps. The next step is to make the content of this redirect page a bit more elegant.</description>
<title>Custom redirect page for a smooth transition between idling Heroku dynos and fully functional apps</title><link>https://theDavidBarton.github.io/idling-heroku</link><pubDate>Sun, Feb 2, 2020</pubDate><description>To host my Node/React projects I am using a Free plan on Heroku which has its limitations. The most challenging one is the limited time these dynos are available.</description>
</channel>
</rss>